JOSH DEROCHER

1025 Hancock St Apt 1k Quincy, MA 02169 207.808.0677 contact@thejoshderocher.com thejoshderocher.com github.com/thebedivere Front-end Developer Video Games Blogger Fantasy & Sci-Fi Writer

Summary

Front-end developer with 2 years of professional experience.

Writer with 4 years of professional experience.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Wordpress, Angularjs, MEAN stack, LAMP stack, Linux, Git, Grunt, Sass, Less, Node.js, Express.js, Mongo.db, mSQL, AWS (Amazon Web Services), SSH, Content creation, and writing.

Education

- Business and Creative Writing 2008-2010
 - O Andover College

Work Experience

- University of Massachusetts Boston October 2015 December 2015
 - O Front-end Developer
 - O Created ExpressionEngine templates based on design documents using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Less, Gulp, and Git.
- Homesite Insurance April 2015 October 2015
 - O Front-end Developer
 - O Created website along with UX/UI team to track and manage creative requests.
 - O Created custom Wordpress Plugins and themes using PHP, mySQL, HTML, CSS, and Sass.
 - O Created working prototypes based on wireframes and design documents using HTML, CSS,

	and JavaScript.
0	Used JIRA and Team Foundation Server for version control and project tracking.
Preview Media October 2014 - April 2015	
0	Front-end Developer
0	Designer.
0	Developed and designed websites for clients using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Sass, Grunt, and Git.
● Convener 2014	
0	Growth Hacker
0	Created email templates and client registration pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery,
	Wordpress, AWS, and PHP.
0	Created content for blog and social media.
0	Found creative solutions on a low budget.
Destructoid 2011-2014	
0	Contributing Writer
0	<u>Destructoid.com</u> is one of the largest independent video game blogs, with an average of 3 million monthly pageviews.
0	Reviewed PC games including <u>SimCity</u> , <u>Company of Heroes 2</u> , and <u>X Rebirth</u> .
0	Writing has also been published on BitMob and Front Towards Gamer.
● Shaw's Supermarket 2013-2014	
0	Overnight Stocker
● CVS 2012-2013	
0	Shift Supervisor
Targe	et 2012-2013
0	Electronics
Borde	er's 2008-2009
0	Cashier
● TJ M	axx 2006-2012

O Customer Service Coordinator

Best Buy 2004-2005Cashier